The sun dawned bloodied... two great armies met face to face... and the
earth trembled to the sound of the Zulu death chant!
Zulu Dawn is a adventure, drama, history film directed by Douglas Hickox.
In 1879, the British suffer a great loss at the Battle of
Isandlwana due to incompetent leadership.
Col. Anthony Durnford, played by Burt Lancaster.
Lt. Vereker, played by Simon Ward.
Colonel Pulleine, played by Denholm Elliott.
QSM Bloomfield, played by Peter Vaughan.
Lt. Melvill, played by James Faulkner.
Lt. Coghill, played by Christopher Cazenove.
Zulu Dawn is a 1979 American adventure war film directed by Douglas
Hickox and written by Anthony Storey and Cy Endfield.
It is based on Endfield's book of the same name about the historical Battle of
Isandlwana in 1879 between British and Zulu forces in South Africa.
Zulu Dawn features an ensemble cast led by Burt Lancaster,
Peter O'Toole, Simon Ward, and Nigel Davenport.
Chronologically it precedes the smaller Battle of Rorke's Drift,
which also had opposing British and Zulu forces.
Zulu (1964) was a film about the latter battle.
The film explores themes of fight, british
empire, victory, prequel, battlefield.
The tone is emotional.